MISAKI TIFFANY SHIMIZU

• front end developer •

ABOUT ME

I am a front-end software developer that creates functional and responsive web designs using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and API integrations. I have an educational background in Early Childhood Studies and have worked in the customer service / retail industry for 10+ years. My strong communication and problem-solving skills allow me to find new solutions and explore new ways to code. Seeking to become the next front-end developer for your company.

EDUCATION

2021 - 2022 • Juno College of Technology Web Development Bootcamp

2019 - 2020 • Humber College Graduate Certificate Event Management

2014 - 2019 • Ryerson University BA Early Childhood Studies

PROJECTS

Daily Dad Jokes Site Link GitHub Link

For this group project, I used React to build an interactive app where users can select a category of photos, input their own dad jokes, and display the results through a carousel. Through the use of Git, we were able to collaborate and successfully produce the request from the client.

Word Search Site Link GitHub Link

I created this app using the Merriam Webster API and exploring React and Axios calls. The user is able to look up a word in the search bar and the API will pull the results and display a definition, pronunciation, and phonetics.

The Music Mood Generator

To create this interactive app I utilized JavaScript, API, and SASS to allow users to select a mood and generate a song based on their selected mood. Users are able to view data pulled from the API that displays the album cover, song title, artist, and an audio clip of the song.

WORK HISTORY

Community Foundation of Mississauga

2020 - 2021

GitHub Link

Site Link

Event Assistant

- Coordinated pre-and post-event planning with a team of 25 staff serving 150 customers.
- Juggled multiple projects and tasks to ensure high quality and timely delivery.
- Procured a team of 30 volunteers to help support two events.
- Created two event websites according to established standards and with high accuracy and efficiency.

Uniqlo 2018 - 2020

Sales Associate

• Worked alongside retail representatives to boost sales by enhancing product presentations and advertising collateral.

- Delivered high level of assistance by locating products and checking store system for merchandise at other sites.
- Maintained organized, presentable merchandise to drive continuous sales.

SKILLS

Communication	HTML5, CSS3, SASS	RESTful API	Performance Testing,
Problem Solving	JavaScript (ES6, ES5)	Responsive Designs	Load testing & Debugging
Customer Service	React	Version Control (Git)	
Critical Thinking	JQuery	Continuous Learner	

VOLUNTEER

Juno College of Technology

2022 - Present

Mentor

- Assist current students in the Web Development BootCamp.
- Provide resources and advice on how to resolve an issue.
- Scaffold and troubleshoot issues with code.

Community Foundation of Mississauga

2020 - 2021

Event Volunteer

- Took meeting notes and created monthly meeting agenda presentations.
- Coordinated with staff, volunteers, and the board of directors.
- Assisted the Event Manager with the run-of-show and communications with tech teams.